# Nguyen Quoc Anh — Data Scientist

↑ TheQuantScientist | in andrewfinance | ✓ anhnguyen.aiml@gmail.com | 1+84 585775676 | ♦ Porfolio

## **SUMMARY**

Dynamic and passion-driven senior Economics and Finance Undergraduate student. Experienced in Data Science with 2 years of academic research in applied Machine Learning. Collaborated with EU research institutions and global Ph.D. scientists. Leading AI/ML projects on predictive modeling. Assisted research in Computer Vision and differential mathematical modeling.

## **EDUCATION**

### **Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology**

Bachelor of Business, Economics and Finance

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam 2021-2024

## AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Deep Learning - Feature Engineering - Data Mining - Data Visualization - Data Analytics - Data Storytelling - Quantitative Analysis - Financial Reporting - Financial Modeling - Investment Research - Portfolio Risk Management - Project Management

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### AI/ML Researcher, (RMIT University)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam 03/2023 - present

- Crawled and processed over 72,000 healthcare data points from PhysioNet, deployed time-sensitive learning to solve irregular data.
- Developed and fine-tuned deep Neural Network models on S&P 500 stocks for forecasting, achieving 65% swing-trading accuracy.
- Labeled time series for binary classification, designed technical indicators, trained Image Models, reducing error metrics by 75%.
- Led and mentored 5 research groups to deploy projects from scratch. Compiled cryptographic algorithms and notations for IoT security.

#### AI Systems and LLMs Trainer, (Outlier)

Freelance, Remote 04/2024 - present

- Trained 8 AI bots to be proficient in Vietnamese, engineered LLMs logic in consecutive prompting, surpassing ChatGPT-40 fluency.
- Applied copywriting on AI prompts to mirror native Vietnamese dialogues, semantic fine-tuned until reached 90% response rationality.
- Monitored systems' dialogues for rhetorical error, flagged over 80 syntax bugs to Team Lead for review, enhancing overall NLP systems.

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Detecting Intraday Crypto Price Movements Using Hierarchical Vision Transformers**

04/2024 - 07/2024

- Fetched 2-year hourly crypto data, transformed arbitrary intervals into images, embedded static info as metadata for optimal training.
- Ensured label balance, engineered MA and RSI indicators, developed correlation heatmaps between OHLCV and engineered datasets.
- Reduced intercorrelation by 53%, reached 95% accuracy, 91% AUROC, and 90% AUPRC with Swin Transformer over ViT and DeiT.

#### Phu Nhuan Jewelry Company Valuation Report for Q1/2024 Investment (Distinction)

03/2024 - 04/2024

- Analysed PNJ financial state, benchmarking CAPM, DDM, P/E models. Recommended BUY strategy despite OVERVALUED signal.
- Interpreted 5-year financial reports, identified 56% post-2022 and 21.6% YoY increase in 2024, surpassing peers and industry median.
- Detected PNJ's leverage for expansion, recommending target price of VND105 thousand for risk-seeking investors to optimize profit.

## **Phase Space Reconstructed Neural ODE for Financial Time Series Forecasting**

01/2023 - 03/2024

- Programmed thus hyperparameter-tuning NODE for time series regression, optimized model with 3:1 embeddings and time delays ratio.
- Deployed Takens's Theorem to reconstruct 3D phase space, capturing 65% of cyclical and long-term dependencies across industries.
- Applied TimeSeriesSplit and 5-fold validation, improved MAE and RMSE metrics by 70%, outperforming LSTM, Transformer, SVR.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] **Anh Nguyen\*** and Son Ha. "Transforming Stock Price Forecasting: Deep Learning Architectures and Strategic Feature Engineering". In: *MDAI 2024 Proceedings* (2024). **CORE B**. DOI: https://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4729146.
- [2] **Anh Nguyen\***, Son Ha, and Hieu Thai. "Phase Space Reconstructed Neural Ordinary Differential Equations Model for Financial Forecasting". In: *PACIS 2024 Proceedings* (2024). **CORE A.** https://aisel.aisnet.org/pacis2024/.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Data Science & AI: TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Numpy, Scikit-learn, XGBoost, (Vision) Transformers, Fastai, Cloud GPU
- Data Analytics: Power BI, Excel, R, MySQL, Python (Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Geoplotlib), PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Financial Analysis: Auditing, Financial Reporting, Budget Forecasting, Cost Analysis, Tax Planning, Profit Optimization
- Digital Tools: Canva Pro, PowerPoint, LaTeX, Figma, ChatGPT 4, ClaudeAI, Gemini, Slack, Tableau, Google Analytics

## **HONORS & ACCOLADES**

Breakthrough Lead Researcher   RMIT News	Aug. 2024
Conference Presenter   Pacific Asia Conference on Information Systems	July. 2024
Invited Peer Reviewer   Springer, IEEE, Elsevier, ICPR, Nature	Jan. 2024
Finalist (CNN-BiLSTM-GRU)   RMIT Impact	Jan. 2024
Conference Presenter   Digital3 International Conference	Oct. 2023
Conference Presenter   ICYREB 2023	Sep. 2023
Project Love Meter Winner   RMIT Showcase	Nov. 2023
Certified Python for Machine Learning and SQL for Data Analytics   NASBA	Nov. 2023

## **VOLUNTEER**

#### Academic Research Peer Reviewer. (WoS Record)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam 01/2024 - present

- Assessed 20 papers for Q1-Q2 journals of IEEE Access.
- Evaluated 10 papers for Computers & Electrical Engineering of Elsevier (Q1 Journal).
- Examined 4 papers for the International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR 2024).
- Critiqued 4 papers for Humanities & Social Sciences Communications of Nature (Q1 Journal).

#### Supporter of Con Duong Xanh Charity Group, Member

**Dong Nai, Vietnam** 01/2024 - present

- Constructed and repaired roads for Truc Lam Tri Duc Zen **Monastery**, hence ensuring safe access for visitors and religious **practitioners**.
- Planted trees and seeds around a **10-hectare** temple land, contributing to the **beautification** and ecological **sustainability** of the temple.
- Assisted monks in **cleaning** and **cooking** daily meals, supporting the monastery's operations to ensure a **harmonious** living environment.
- Promoted **green** campaigns, marketing future **charity** activities to connections. Maintained continuous and stable cash flow for groups.

#### Academic and Communication English Tutor, Freelance

**Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam** 02/2021 - 11/2023

- 1:1 tutored 7 students (2 Onsite and 5 Online), taught basic communication English for DM&C's Korean CEO and a native Japanese.
- Focused on **IELTS** Academic training (Reading, Writing, and Speaking) thus designing **personalized** study plans for each participant.
- Consulted more than 200 undergraduate Bachelor students' work, earned 1 Bronze medal in the National English Test for the Gifted.
- Allocated 50% of monthly freelance income to the local impoverished, contributing over VND50 million to local medical aid programs.

## LANGUAGES

• Vietnamese [Native]

• English [IELTS 7.0]